# ALPHONES KIPROTICH BETT

Phone number: +254728418311

Email: alphoneskiprotich03@gmail.com

An IT Support enthusiast with experience in Networking, Front-end Web Development, Programming Languages (C#, Python) and Adobe Photoshop (Social Media Graphics, Flyers, Photo Editing, Logo Design, Posters). I'm an industrious person who believes in hard work, commitment, determination and upholds integrity as core values in life.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**COMPANY: KENYA REVENUE AUTHORITY(KRA)** 

**JOB TITLE: INTERN** 

FROM: JAN 2023 – DEC 2024

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Provide technical assistance to staff and customers on hardware and software-related issues.
- Install, configure, and troubleshoot computer systems, hardware, and software.
- Monitor system performance and troubleshoot any issues.
- Networking-Termination of Ethernet Cables, Configuration of Networks and connection.
- Monitoring and fault management.
- Setting up workstation for new staffs and assisting in connecting projector during staff meetings and training
- User and system support.
- KRA PIN registration and retrieval.
- Installation of ETIMS to taxpayers and training them on how the system works.
- Individual and non-individual returns filing for various tax-obligations.
- Relating with taxpayers by sharing knowledge where need be and assist in generating payment slips,
  amending tax returns and generating tax compliance certificates.
- Prepare demand notices and agency notices and sending to taxpayers and various banks.

COMPANY: MINISTRY OF ROADS, TRANSPORT AND PUBLIC WORKS.

**JOB TITLE:** ICT INDUSTRIAL ATTACHMENT

**FROM:** MAY 2022 – AUGUST 2022

## RESPONSIBILITIES

- Installation and configuration of networking equipment.
- Networking-Termination of Ethernet Cables, Configuration of Networks and connection.
- Data protection, updating virus protection software and creating firewalls
- Troubleshooting and resolving networking issues in departments within the State Departments.
- User and system support.
- Monitoring and fault management.
- Operating Systems installation and Partitioning and formatting of hard disks.
- Removing dust in CPUs in different Departments using Air Blower machine.

## **EDUCATION**

AUGUST,2018-OCTOBER, 2022

SOUTH EASTERN KENYA UNIVERSITY: BSc. COMPUTER SCIENCE

JANUARY, 2014-DECEMBER, 2017

KABIANGA HIGH SCHOOL: KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION(KCSE)

JANUARY, 2005 - DECEMBER, 2013

**KAPKWEN PRIMARY SCHOOL**: KENYA CERTIFICATE OF PRIMARY EDUCATION EDUCATION(KCPE)

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

MAY, 2024 - AUG, 2024

## CLOUD AND NETWORK SECURITY: CYBER SHUJAA

Network standards, models and protocols, Examining Network layers, Securing Network layers, Cloud Computing, Cloud identity and access management (IAM), Securing Cloud Network and Remote Access, Securing Cloud Compute and Storage, Securing software development and operations, Cloud, Monitoring and Incidence Response, Vulnerability assessment and penetration testing (VAPT) and Identity and Access Management.

AUG, 2023 – OCT, 2023

## PCAP: AFRICAN ADVANCED LEVEL TELECOMMUNICATIONS INSTITUTE

Introduction to python and computer programming, data types, Boolean values, function tuples, dictionaries, data processing and basic operators. Programming essentials in python.

MAY, 2023 – JUL, 2023

#### CYBERSECURITY ESSENTIALS: KENYATTA UNIVERSITY

Global implications of cyber threats, ways in which networks are vulnerable to attack, impact of cyber-attacks and approach to threat detection and defense.

## **PROJECTS**

- i. **SEKU CU Management System:** Developed using HTML, CSS, MS SQL Server, JavaScript languages to aid and ease management of services at SEKU Christian Union.
- ii. Covid-19 Project: Windows Form Project to create, read, edit and delete covid-19 patients' information in a database (Microsoft SQL Server, C#).
- iii. Bank Accounts CRUD Project: Angular cli inline table project to integrate Web API with MS SQL Server database that create, read, update and delete bank accounts. (C#, Angular JS).
- iv. School Management System: Window Forms project that create, read, update and delete student, teacher, subject, enrollment and attendance information in a database (MS SQL Server)

## **SKILLS**

- Networking: Termination of Ethernet Cables, Configuration of Networks and connection.
- Problem-solving and leadership skills.
- Operating Systems installation and Partitioning and formatting of hard disks.
- HTML, CSS, JS, Angular JS C# (.NET Core Frameworks, Window Forms).
- Database development, maintenance and administration using SQL (Microsoft SQL Server & MySQL).
- Adobe Photoshop (Photo editing, Logo Design, Banners, Flyers, Poster)
- System administration & management.

## **INERESTS**

- Learning new Technologies through documentation and the internet.
- Interested in doing volunteers or community work during my free time.
- Participating in social activities i.e. playing volleyball, listening music and watching movies and international football games.

## **REFEREES**

1. DR. CASPER SHIKALI

Lecturer (ICT)- South Eastern Kenya University

TEL:0720832863

Email: cshikali@seku.ac.ke

2. MR. CHARLES KIPRONO TURGUT

Branch Manager- KRA Naivasha TSO

Email: charles.turgut@kra.go.ke

TEL:0723926789

3. MR. CORNELIUS TONUI

CEO-Micropoint Systems, Nairobi

Email: ctonui@gmail.com

TEL:0720472020